<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<books>
  
	<book ID="Brothers_Tortoises_BabyShaileStory" Title="{{W|Two Watervine Farmers}}" Format="Auto" Margins="1,2,2,2">
<page>"Come on, touch it." The first farmer poked at the egg nestled between fronds with his vinereaper's handle. The thin layer of ice around the ivory sphere rustled and popped before reforming quickly.

"Sultans, I already told you! No way. I ain't touching that thing, and that's the end of it. Now come on, we've got a harvest to finish." The second farmer crossed his arms, thinking himself resolute and unwavering.

The first farmer poked the egg again, disturbing the ice once more. Thin cracks ran alongside the frozen watervine, plant matter reluctantly giving way once devoid of its flexibility. He had a plan, one that would undoubtedly sway his companion's mind.

"What if I throw in a copper nugget? Maybe a few drams of water?" he tentatively offered, testing the negotiation grounds.

The second farmer's brow furrowed, his resolve melting quickly when faced with the untold possibilities of a copper nugget. Still, even touching that egg could prove unwise, especially if-

"Actually, make it two copper nuggets. I'm in a generous mood today," the first farmer added, seeing his companion pondering his initial offer.

That settled it: with a reluctant sigh, the second farmer knelt by the egg, setting his trusty vinereaper down. A moment of hesitation caught him there. 

"Are you sure it's safe?" he probed the first farmer, fishing for any support he could find.

The answer came a tad too quickly: "Of course it is. Otherwise, I wouldn't be asking you to do it."

Still, two copper nuggets are two copper nuggets. 

{{icy|The second farmer slowly reached out to the egg.}}</page>
	</book>

	<book ID="Brothers_Tortoises_TravelerJournal" Title="{{W|Audio Travelog CXXXIX}}" Format="Auto" Margins="1,2,2,2">
<page>[[{{w|3rd of Simmun Ut}}]]

Speculator Ptodelia reporting. The edge of the Moghra'yi is in view, and I shall not lament leaving the salt bluffs and cliffs behind. The rolling dunes look almost gentle in comparison, were it not for their unpleasant dwellers. Caravan leader Timuqq told me today the caravan will be making a detour, the saltback refusing to cross a part of the desert. They would not tell me why -- dromad trade secrets, I wager. I shall see about leaving the caravan before that, as I see little point in making my route longer than it needs to be. Speculator Ptodelia, out.


[[{{w|6th of Simmun Ut}}]]

{{emote|*Heavy wind makes most of the entry indecipherable.*}}


[[{{w|7th of Simmun Ut}}]]

Speculator Ptodelia reporting. I split from the caravan four days ago, but did not report on it. Yesterday, Qudish winds rose up eastward in the early morning. By High Salt Sun, a proper saltstorm was raging -- Academy be thanked, experimental tracheal filters are as useful east of the Moghra'yi as they are west. With vision compromised, I stayed close to the packbot and happened upon some sort of...

{{emote|*An old, masculine voice calls out in the distance, and the next words are uttered away from the recorder.*}}

No Warden, I am logging my travels for posterity... Yes, on my machine. I give you my word I will not include the location of this place. I shall leave a copy, if that eases your mind.

... some hut by an old boneyard. In accordance with the Principles I shall document it, but the old warden bids me to keep its location secret. In quite a fascinating way, the eastern saltbacks seem to naturally gravitate toward this place in their old age. Unlike what I previously observed in the salt bluffs...

{{emote|*The rest of the entry is a thesis on compared saltback cultural traditions, concluded by the usual "Speculator Ptodelia, out".*}}</page>
	</book>

</books>